Hello and welcome again, to the course.
Olá, e bem-vindos de volta ao curso.
Before we get too deep in the lectures here,
Antes de nos aprofundarmos na aula,
I want to preview the interactive hands on labs platform called Qwiklabs, and
quero mostrar os laboratórios práticos chamados Qwiklabs
how you'll actually be practicing a lot of the things that you're going to learn here
e como você praticará muitas das coisas mostradas aqui
inside of real Google Cloud Platform accounts.
em contas reais do Google Cloud Platform.
But you don't need your own credentials,
Não precisa de credenciais,
those are actually going to be provided for you.
elas serão fornecidas a você.
So, just take a look at how the lab platform is set up.
Veja como a plataforma funciona.
Inside of Coursera, you're actually going to see a lab or
No Coursera, você verá um laboratório
an item that's marked out for an external tool to open up, and
ou um item marcado para ser aberto ferramenta externa.
you're going to click on that tool.
Clique nessa ferramenta.
After that you're going to see a Start Lab button in green and
Depois, você verá um botão "Start Lab" verde
a timer associated with it for you to complete the lab in that duration.
e um cronômetro para concluir o laboratório nesse tempo.
After you click that Start Lab, credentials for your student accounts
Ao clicar em "Start Lab", as credenciais da sua conta de aluno
are automatically going to be provided to you in a new box is going to pop up.
serão fornecidas automaticamente em uma nova caixa.
In addition, there's going to be another button that says
Além disso, haverá outro botão,
Open Google Console in yellow.
"Open Google Console", em amarelo.
And once you open that up,
Ao clicar nele,
that's going to ask you to log in to the Google Cloud Platform
o sistema pedirá para você se conectar ao GCP.
with the key caveat and you log in with a student account and
Lembre-se, você precisa se conectar com a conta de aluno,
not your personal account should you already have one set up.
não com sua conta pessoal, caso tenha uma.
And last but not the least,
Por fim,
we'll do a few demos and walk-throughs of what the UI looks like.
faremos algumas demonstrações e veremos como é a interface.
So, let's take a look.
Vamos ver.
So, inside an example Coursera course,
Em um curso de exemplo,
you're going to come across a lab that looks something like this.
você verá um laboratório que parece com este.
This is just an example, this is lab 0 but
Este exemplo usa o laboratório 0,
it could be any of the labs that you might find.
mas pode ser qualquer laboratório.
Once you clicked on that,
Depois de clicar,
you'll see a check box that's going to authorize the lab to run and
você verá uma caixa de seleção que autoriza a execução do laboratório.
you accept the terms and conditions for Coursera and you click on Open Tool.
Aceite os termos e condições do Coursera e clique em "Open Tool".
And once you click open tool, it's going to bring you to the Qwiklabs environment
Isso levará você ao ambiente do Qwiklabs.
and a couple of key things to notice here.
Há algumas coisas que você precisa observar.
On the right hand side is your instructions paying for the actual lab.
O lado direito mostra as instruções do laboratório.
Now this lab's a medal lab, it's all about Qwiklabs in general.
Este é um laboratório sobre o Qwiklabs em geral.
But whatever you course is, this is what the instructions for
Qualquer que seja o curso, é aqui que ficarão as instruções
completing the lab are going to take place.
para concluir o laboratório.
So you always want to keep this prompt open.
Mantenha esse prompt sempre aberto.
Now once you actually click Start Lab, a provision instance of the Google Cloud
Depois de clicar em "Start Lab", uma instância provisionada do GCP
platform complete with any additional instances or say you're working with VMs.
com as instâncias adicionais, se você trabalhar com VMs,
If there is something that the lab provider wanted you to have,
ou qualquer outra coisa que você precisará ter
it's actually going to be created inside of this lab instance for you,
será crada para você dentro dessa instância do laboratório.
which is a great thing, it's a Sandbox instance.
Isso é ótimo, é uma instância de Sandbox.
Now, once you noticed I click Start Lab, I have 15 minutes to complete this lab.
Depois de clicar em "Start Lab", eu tenho 15 minutos para fazer tudo.
I promise you that the timers are going to be associated with additional padding for
Prometo que o tempo será associado ao esforço adicional
the labs that you're going to do.
de cada laboratório.
This isn't going to mean it's going to take us 15 minutes,
Pode não demorar 15 minutos,
this will take as maybe about five minutes.
podemos terminar em cinco.
Style-wise, I mentioned before, you have the username and password, and
Como eu disse, você tem o nome de usuário, a senha
a project ID.
e o código do projeto.
What I'll ask you to do now is click on Open Google Console.
Agora, clique em "Open Google Console".
And once you've opened Google Console,
Depois de abrir o console,
you'll be be asked to sign up with your email.
você precisará fazer login com seu e-mail.
Now the key thing here is if you use google resources before immediately you
Se você usa os recursos do Google com frequência,
start typing your personal email I do it all the time make sure you go back to your
pode ser que comece a digitar seu e-mail pessoal.
lab credentials screen and copy and paste the user name that's autogenerated here.
Volta para as credenciais, copie e cole o nome gerado nela.
It's going to be unique for you and it's actually going to be unique for
Ele será exclusivo para você e para cada laboratório
every lab that you run.
que você fizer.
So it we'll be creating a new soon account for each lab that you run.
Nós criaremos uma nova conta para cada laboratório.
Copy and paste that password which is going to be different from mine, so
Copie e cole a senha, que será diferente da minha,
don't worry about copying that down.
então não precisa copiar nada.
Click Next in your browser, paste in that password, accept the terms,
Clique em "Next" no navegador, cole a senha e aceite os termos.
Don't worry about setting up a secondary phone number,
Não se preocupe em configurar um número de telefone,
accept the terms of the Google Cloud Platform.
só aceite os termos do Google Cloud Platform.
And once you see a screen that looks like this, then you're good to go.
Esta tela mostra que está tudo pronto.
Make sure, key tidbit, is this is your project selector,
Este é o seletor do projeto,
it should be this auto generated Qwiklabs alpha numeric.
ele precisa ter um código alfanumérico gerado automaticamente pelo Qwiklabs.
If you happen to see something that says either select a project or if you see
Se você vir a mensagem "Select a project"
something that says Qwiklabs resources, you actually want to click on this.
ou "Qwiklabs resources", clique nele,
And make sure to select your alphanumeric Qwiklabs' ID, and then go ahead and
selecione o código alfanumérico do Qwiklabs
Once you're within here you're good to go.
Agora, está tudo pronto.
So follow the instructions for the rest of the lab.
Siga as instruções do laboratório.
It's going to guide you through what products and
Ele guiará você pelos produtos
services you're going to be working with.
e serviços com que você trabalhará.
You can access the menu of products and services in the upper left hand
Acessar o menu "Products and Services" no canto esquerdo
corner here, or if it's a lab that's working for Cloud Shell.
ou, se o laboratório estiver no Cloud Shell,
All the way up here, is the button to activate Cloud Shell,
o botão para ativar o Cloud Shell está aqui.
which will open up that terminal instance for Google Cloud Platform.
Ele abrirá a instância de terminal do Google Cloud Platform.
Last few things, back here, you see that our timer is automatically running still,
Estamos quase terminando. O tempo ainda está correndo.
once you're completed with the lab, you're done with it.
Depois de terminar o laboratório,
Or if you wanted to take a another attempt at the lab,
ou se quiser tentar novamente,
you have upwards of three attempts for lab which is great.
você tem até três tentativas para cada laboratório.
So say you want to run to the lab very quickly the first time and
Você pode fazer tudo rápido na primais vez
then experiment and explore within the second time.
e explorar mais na segunda tentativa.
You are welcome to do that for a couple of times.
É possível fazer isso duas vezes.
Now make sure in order to get completion starts properly recorded click on End Lab.
Para registrar o status de conclusão, clique em "End Lab".
You'll be faced with a prompt that says, are you all done?
Você verá um aviso para perguntar se terminou tudo.
Once you click End Lab, your project, any data sets, anything that you've been
Ao clicar em "End Lab", o projeto, os conjuntos de dados
working with inside of this Ssandbox project is going to be deleted.
e todos os outros elementos do projeto de sandbox serão excluídos.
So make sure if you have any queries that you're running or
Se tiver alguma consulta em execução
any interesting that you have saved inside of your Google Cloud Platform Qwiklabs'
ou algo interessante salvo na conta do Qwiklabs,
account, that you copy and paste those and save them some where else.
lembre-se de copiar e salvar em outro lugar.
Perhaps in your own personal Google Cloud Platform account or
Talvez na sua conta pessoal do Google Cloud Platform
some where locally on our machine.
ou localmente no seu computador.
And once you've clicked End Lab, then you can add feedback for the lab, and
Depois de clicar em "End Lab", você pode deixar seu feedback
you can continue moving around the rest of the course in Coursera.
e continuar com o restante do curso no Coursera.
So again, quick recap, the only key things to remember is click and
Recapitulando, você precisa clicar em
Open Tool that will open up Qwiklabs.
"Open Tool", que abrirá o Qwiklabs.
The second is in order to get those credentials here on the left hand side,
Depois, para conseguir estas credenciais no lado esquerdo,
you have to click Start Lab, which again, kicks off the timer.
clique em "Start Lab", o que iniciará o cronômetro.
And there's no way to pause once the lab has started, but again,
Não há como pausar o cronômetro depois de começar,
keep in mind you have multiple attempts.
mas você tem várias tentativas.
And lastly, click on End Lab when you're ready to
Por fim, clique em "End Lab" quando estiver pronto
complete out the lab that you've been working on.
para concluir o laboratório.
That's it, good luck with the labs that come later on and enjoy the course.
É isso. Boa sorte com os próximos laboratórios, e aproveite o curso.